

# **Ramon Lorente**

**♀** 150 NW 96th Ave Apt 103, Pembroke Pines, Florida, 33024, United States **☒** ramon\_lorente@yahoo.com

9563362323

## **Profile**

I am an international chess master and graduated from the Full Stack Web and Mobile Development Bootcamp at Nucamp ☑. I have a bachelor's degree in Physical Education from Cuba, and I am currently working at Franklin Academy Pembroke Pines in Florida.

I discovered my passion for programming at the beginning of the pandemic. I have been self-studying and working hard in learning technologies like HTML, CSS, SASS, JavaScript, React JS, Node JS, Java, SQL, and others.

I am currently developing my skills as a Java Developer by studying Udemy courses and creating personal projects that I am including on my GitHub account ②. I am applying to entry-level Java Developer jobs, but I am open to Frontend developer projects as well.

I am the father of a four-year-old son and a husband, living in Pembroke Pines, Florida. I have a strong will and desire to learn, and I am determined to work hard to become a successful software engineer.

## **Education**

06/2021 – 11/2021 Online	Full Stack Web & Mobile Development Bootcamp, Nucamp
2004 – 2010 Holguin, Cuba	Bachelor of Education in Physical Education, University of Science in Physical Education and Sports GPA: 3.3358

## Languages

• English • Spanish • Portuguese

## **Professional Experience**

08/2021 – present Pembroke Pines, Florida	Middle School Chess Teacher, Franklin Academy Pembroke Pines
06/2019 – 09/2020 White Plains, New York	Master Chess Instructor, National Scholastic Chess Foundation ♂

08/2018 – 05/2019 Elementary Chess Teacher, Franklin Academy Sunrise

04/2016 – 05/2018 Elementary Bilingual Instructor K-1, Hawthorne Elementary ☑

101/2015 – 03/2016 Professional Chess Coach, Brownsville Independent School District ☑

Brownsville, Texas

SASS

## Certificates

Full Stack Web and Mobile Bachelor of Education and Development Physical Education

Nucamp University of Science in Physical Education and Sports, Cuba

Skills

Java JavaScript

HTML CSS

**React JS** 

React Native Node JS

MongoDB Bootstrap

Material UI Adobe InDesign

Adobe Illustrator Adobe Photoshop

Chess Teamwork

Creative thinking Analytical thinking

**Publications** 

2018 Chess 4 Math Kindergarten book ☑

2018 Chess News, ChessBase ☑

**Projects** 

GitHub Account 🗷